(サクラ)ここじゃないわ！
This isn't the place.
《ナルト : どこだ…!?》
Where are you?
《サクラ : 私たち…➡
We've...finally made it this far!
ようやく ここまで来たのよ！》
サスケ～!!
Sasuke!
(カブト)まだ…
見つけられないみたいだね。
It seems...
they still haven't been able
to find him...
ここのアジトも 結構 広いからね。
This hideout is rather large,
after all.
苦労すると思うよ。
I think it'll be
a struggle for them.
詳しい地図でもあれば
話は 別だが…。
It'd be a different story
if they had a detailed map...
あいにくと それは ボクの頭の中だ。
But unfortunately,
it's inside my head.
(ヤマト)そう言えば ボクが➡
Did you think if you said that,
道案内しろ とでも
言うと思ったか？
I'd ask you to show me
the way?
…フッ。
ボクの任務は
ここで キミを見張ることだ。
My mission is to stand guard
over you here...
１人で キミを
本拠地に連れていくような➡
I've no intention of doing
something so risky...
as to take you inside your base.
リスクを 冒す気はない。
フッフッフッフ。
ソイツは 残念だ…。
That's too bad...
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ここにも いない…。
He's not in here, either.
This is the last room
on this floor.
(サイ)ここのフロアは
この部屋で 終わりだ。
次のフロアへ 行こう。
Let's go to the next floor.
あぁ…！
Right...
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ナルト君！
Naruto...!
二手に分かれて 捜してるんだ。
We're split up
into two search teams.
慌てず 少し 休んだほうが…。
You should stay calm
and rest a little...
う… うるせえ…！
Shut up...!
休んでなんか いられっか…！
I can't be resting!
もう少しで… サスケに…。
We're so close...to Sasuke...
《クッソ…。
Damn it...!
九尾化したときのダメージが まだ…》
The damage I took when I morphed
into the Nine-Tails still hasn't...
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ここにも いない！
He's not in here, either...
サクラ… 少し 焦りすぎだ。
Sakura...
You're getting too impatient...
ここは 大蛇丸の アジトの中…。
This is the inside
of Orochimaru's hideout...
It's possible that traps
have been set.
罠が張られている可能性も ある。
焦りすぎると
ヤツに 気づかれる恐れもある！
If we get too impatient,
he might find out that we're here.
それは わかってます！
でも サスケ君が！
I know that!
But! Sasuke is...!
サクラ！
Sakura!
ナルトのほうは…？
まだだ。
What about Naruto...?
Not yet.
だが サスケを発見するのも
時間の問題だ。
But it's only a matter of time
before we find Sasuke...
慎重に行動しろ。
Act with caution!
はい。
I will...
The Picture Book's Story
気がついたみたいだね？
It seems you're awake...
サイ…。
Sai?
まったく キミは よく似ている。
Boy...you really resemble him.
兄さんにだよ。
My older brother...
He was talkative and
he would lose his head...
口やかましく あわてんぼうで…➡
品がなくて… それに チン…。
He had no manners...
and his equipment was--
まぁ… それはいいや。
Well, never mind...
だけど そう…
キミのように 何をするにも➡
But yeah...like you,
he went all-out with
everything he did.
必死だった。
キミを見ていると…➡
When I look at you,
なんだか 兄さんのことを…。
I kind of remember him...
サイ…？
Sai?
サイ… サイってばよ。
Sai...! Hey, Sai!
どうしたんだ？
What's the matter?
(サイ)思い出した…
思い出したんだ。
I remembered...
I remembered...!
You mean...
それって…！
兄さんに見せたかった…➡
This is what I wanted
to show him.
２人の夢の絵を。
The picture of our dreams...
(大蛇丸)さて… サイ…。
Now then...Sai...
which side are you going
to take?
あなたは どちら側に
つくのかしら？
潜影蛇手！
Striking Shadow Snake!
やはり そちら側のようね…。
Just as I thought. It seems
you're taking that side, huh...?
サイとやら…。
Sai or whatever...
ここは オレが止めるってばよ。
I'll stop him here.
サイ… お前は サスケを捜してくれ！
Sai, you go find Sasuke.
早く！
わかった。
Hurry!
Okay... I'll find Sasuke...
and save him!
サスケ君は ボクが見つけて助け出す。
サスケ君を連れ戻しに
きたってわけね。
So you came to take back
Sasuke, huh...?
キミの執念はすごいけど
そう うまくいくかしらね？
Your persistence is impressive,
but will it really be that easy?
エロ仙人や 綱手のバアちゃんと同じ➡
It doesn't make any difference that
you're one of the Legendary Sannin
伝説の三忍だろうと 関係ねえ！
like the Pervy Sage and
Grandma Tsunade!
お前を倒して サスケを連れ帰る！
I'll defeat you...
and take Sasuke back!
ここもいない…。
He's not here, either...
Naruto's Chakra...
ナルトのチャクラだ。
It appears something
has happened...
何かあったらしい… いくよ。
Let's go!
はい。
Right!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Striking Shadow Snake!
潜影蛇手！
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
さっきの勢いはどうしたの？
What happened to all
your energy from earlier?
Your power...
The power of the Nine-Tails...
あなたの力は… 九尾の力は➡
こんなものじゃないでしょ。
There must be more to it
than this, right?
You're the one
who hurt Sakura, Naruto.
((サクラを傷つけたのは➡
キミだよ ナルト…。
You'll end up tormenting yourself
if you rely on the power...
これからも
この九尾の力に頼れば➡
自分自身を
苦しめることになるし➡
of the Nine-Tails from here on.
仲間を傷つけてしまう
力にも なりえる。
And it could turn into a power
that hurts your friends.
今回のようにね。
Like what happened this time.
If you want to save Sasuke,
do it with your own power.
サスケを助けたいなら
キミ自身の力で助け出せ。
If you want to see Sasuke...
サスケの姿を見たいなら➡
do it with your own eyes,
not the Nine-Tails'.
九尾の目ではなく 自分の目で…。
そして サクラを守りたいなら➡
And if you want
to protect Sakura...
(九尾の力ではなく 自分の力で))
do it with your own power,
not the Nine-Tails'!
フフ… 少しは本気を
見せてちょうだい。
Show me all you've got.
潜影蛇手！
Striking Shadow Snake!
Orochimaru again, huh...?
また大蛇丸か。
《大蛇丸は ナルト君が
足止めしてくれている…》
Naruto is stalling Orochimaru...
《隊長とサクラさんも
ナルト君の援護に向かったはず》
And I'm sure the Captain
and Sakura...
have gone to back up Naruto...
忍法 超獣偽画。
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
Naruto...
(大蛇丸)ナルト君… キミは
まだ生かしといてあげるわ！
I'll still let you live...
せいぜい 暁を １人でも多く
始末してちょうだいね！
Please dispose of as many members
of the Akatsuki as you can, okay?
なっ なに!?
Wh-What?!
More importantly,
I've got business with Sai...
それより私は
サイのほうに用があるから。
(大蛇丸)これで失礼するわ。
So I'll be leaving now.
はぁ…。
サイは？
サイは サスケを捜してるってばよ！
Where's Sai?
Sai's looking for Sasuke!
大蛇丸に見つかる前に
何とかしなきゃ！
We have to do something
before Orochimaru finds him!
I'll have to use up all of
my Chakra,
チャクラ 使い切っちまうけど➡
多重影分身で捜してみる！
but I'll try searching with
my Multiple Shadow Clone...
ヤマト隊長とサクラちゃんは
そっち側を頼む！
Captain Yamato and Sakura,
you guys search that side.
(サクラ)これ…。
What's this...?
うん。
He...was able to remember...
アイツ 思い出せたんだ！
それは 兄さんに見せたかった➡
He said that's the picture of dreams
he wanted to show his older brother.
２人の夢の絵なんだってさ！
They're both smiling...
２人とも笑ってる…。
あぁ… その絵を描いたとき➡
Yeah... He smiled for real for
the first time when he drew that...
初めてホントに笑ってた 心から…。
Smiled from the bottom of his heart.
ん？
こ… これは…。
Wh-What's this...?!
What's the matter?
(サクラ)どうしたんですか？
(ヤマト)サイのバッグの中にあった…。
It was in Sai's bag...
これは 暗部の者が
己のターゲットを記す暗殺リスト。
This is an assassination list
that has...
an Anbu Black Ops member's
own targets recorded...
いわば ビンゴブックだ。
It's called a Bingo Book.
暗殺リスト？
An assassination list...?
(サクラ)この×印… 何なんです？
What are these "X" marks?
これは おそらくターゲットを
すでに抹殺したという印だろう。
In all likelihood,
they're marks indicating targets
that have already been eliminated...
なんで そんなものを サイが…。
Why does Sai have such a thing...?
Look at this...
(ヤマト)見ろ！
こ… これって…。
Th-This is...!
なんで
サイの暗殺リストに… サスケの顔が!?
(ヤマト)今日のお題は
ボクも所属していた暗部についてだ。
(ヤマト)正式名称は…
里じゅうから選りすぐりの
忍たちで構成される暗部は➡
正規部隊とは異なり➡
火影直属の部隊として存在する。
(ヤマト)その特殊な任務の性質上
彼らの素性は極秘扱い。
常に 動物の面で顔を覆い➡
その情報は 何重ものセキュリティーで
守られている。
…はずなんだけどね。
ちなみに ボクが尊敬する
カカシ先輩も元暗部。
というわけで これが
その時代の貴重なフィルムだ！
まぁ 当時のことは
多くは語れないけど➡
先輩は 暗部時代も
すごい忍犬使いだったんだよ！
これ観せたこと 先輩には
絶対 内緒にしておいてくれよ！